在这个讲座中，我们将讨论机器人联合控制。那就是我们的实际情况
In this lecture, we're going to talk about Robot Joint Control. That's how do we actually
使机器人移动。这是一个非常重要的问题。所以，使用一些原则
make a robot move. It's a really important problem. So, using some of the principles
我们已经在本课程中学到了什么，我们在这里有一个机器人，我们会说，
that we've already learned about in this course, we have a robot here and we're going to say,
“我希望机器人末端执行器处于这种特殊姿势。”这是一个约束条件
"I want the robot end-effector to be at this particular pose." This is a constraint that
来自我正在尝试的特定任务。我是一个机器人手臂，我想选择
comes from the particular task that I'm trying to do. I'm a robot arm and I want to pick
然后我知道机器人末端执行器必须达到的姿势。
up this particular object then I know the pose that the robot end-effector has to achieve.
现在，我可以使用反向运动学来告诉我角度应该是什么
Now, I can use the inverse kinematics to tell me what should be the angles in the
机器人手臂的关节，以便手臂的末端达到特定的姿势。
joints of the robot arm in order for the end of the arm to get to that particular pose.
所以，我们已经讨论过如何做到这一点。这是反向运动学问题。挑战
So, we’ve talked about how to do this. This is the inverse kinematic problem. The challenge
我们将在本讲座中讨论的是如何实际联合采用
that we’re going to talk about in this lecture is how do I actually make the joint adopt
一个特定的角度。这个关节有一个马达。它里面有一些传感器。所以我们是
a particular angle. The joint’s got a motor in it. It’s got some sensors in it. So we’re
谈谈使关节具有特定角度的控制系统
going to talk about the control system that makes the joint have the particular angle
我们希望它拥有。这是联合控制问题。
that we want it to have. This is the joint control problem.
现在，这个企业试图控制电机的位置来控制角度
Now, this business of trying to control the position of a motor to control the angle of
机器人关节是机电一体化中非常普遍的问题。有很多很多动作
a robot joint is a really common problem in mechatronics. There are many, many motion
控制系统在我们拥有的各种事物中，我们可能甚至都不知道
control systems in all sorts of things that we own that we probably don’t even know
他们在那里。在喷墨打印机中，有一个非常精确的运动控制系统
that they’re there. In an ink jet printer, there is a very precise motion control system
那就是将打印头移到纸上。
that’s moving the printing print head across the paper.
另一个运动控制系统是将纸张向后和向前移动通过打印机。
Another motion control system is moving the paper backwards and forwards through the printer.
机器人吸尘器有一个运动控制系统来控制每个吸尘器的速度
A robot vacuum cleaner has got a motion control system to control the speed of each of its
轮子使其以适当的速度在地板上移动。
wheels so that it moves with the appropriate velocity across the floor.
在计算机或DVD驱动器的硬盘驱动器中，有一个头部
Within a hard disk drive in your computer or within DVD drive, there is a head which
从旋转磁盘读取信息。它必须精确定位
reads the information off the spinning disk. It has to be positioned really precisely over
磁盘的表面。
the disk’s surface.
这种运动控制系统是现代非常普遍的技术
This motion control systems are very, very pervasive pieces of technology in the modern
世界。因此，我们今天要学习的是一个非常特殊的动作案例
world. So, what we’re going to learn about today is a very particular case of a motion
控制系统。它是一个控制机器人关节角度的运动控制系统。
control system. It’s a motion control system that’s controlling the angle of a robot’s joint.